#### Muhammad Ali

Mobile 240-838-8216 Email: ali.wizmen@gmail.com Residence: West Laurel, Maryland Work Authorization: US Citizen

**Professional Summary** 

Oracle Fusion, Cloud and EBS Applications Development and Support with 10 years of industry experience, seeking position as an Oracle Fusion Applications/Data Scientist role which offers key participation, team work tasks, individual challenges and contributes towards achieving personal and organization goals

# **Key Skills**

- Oracle Fusion Order Management and Fusion Advance Pricing technical development and implementation support. Extension framework and Customization in Fusion Order management and Advance Pricing
- Experience working with Scaled Agile Framework SAFe, methodology for development and delivery
- Hands-on development and support experience in Oracle E-Business Suite R12 Supply Chain Procure to Pay (Purchasing, Inventory, Order Management) Discrete Manufacturing (BOM, Routing, WIP, Discrete Jobs), Financials (Payables, Receivables, Fixed Assets, General Ledger) and Human Capital Management (Human Resource Management, Payroll Processing) modules
- Expertise working with Groovy Scripting, Advance Java, Python, Django framework, OBIEE, Oracle 11g, 10g, 9i databases, Advance PL/SQL, Oracle Forms 10g/6i, Reports 10g/6i, SQL \* Loader, E-business Suite R12 Personalization and Extension building, XML and BI Publisher
- Experience in Data Modeling, Relational Database concepts and Entity relation diagrams (ERD), objectoriented modeling and programming and oracle daily business intelligence
- Involved in project planning and scheduling, System design, Functional Specification, Design specification, preparation of impact analysis, Coding, system test plan, testing, code review, coordinating user testing and user training, Project demonstration and Implementation
- Expertise in technical documentation writing in line with Oracle AIMs (Oracle Applications Implementation Methodologies) standards e.g. MD70, CV60, TE40

# **Professional Experience**

# **Principal Consultant**

Oracle Corporation, Columbia, Maryland

03/2015 - Present

Oracle Corporation is a multinational computer technology corporation, headquartered in Redwood Shores, California. The company specializes primarily in developing and marketing database software and technology, cloud engineered systems and enterprise software products.

- Oracle Fusion Supply Chain Order Management and Advance Pricing Development and Support
- Business requirement gathering, code development, deployment, user trainings
- PLSQL Development, Groovy code and different development tools and platforms

# **Senior Programmer Analyst**

06/2014 - 03/2015

CTIS Inc. Health Informatics Company, Rockville, Maryland

CTIS has over 25 years of proven history in providing total informatics solutions to healthcare systems, healthcare professionals and research organizations. National Cancer Institute (NCI USA) is one of the clients of CTIS Inc.

- Development of clinical trial management system to support cancer research and drug development
- Extensive use of Oracle Forms 11g, Reports 11g and SQL/PLSQL 11g for front end and database objects development
- Extensive development work using triggers, packages, APIs and development tools like TOAD, SQL Developer

 Application development and deployment using IBM ClearCase and IBM ClearQuest tools for versioning and control

#### **Techno-Functional Consultant**

05/2010 - 06/2014

AL-Qahtani Pipe Coating Industries, Dammam, Saudi Arabia

Leader in oil pipes coating industry in Saudi Arabia and partner with Oracle, IBM, Microsoft and Sun Microsystems

- Provided implementation support for R12 order management, oracle purchasing, inventory, payables, receivables, fixed assets, general ledger and discrete manufacturing modules
- Developed custom Oracle Forms, custom APIs, data uploading scripts, custom packages and triggers, Ebusiness Suite Personalizaions and developed code for Custom.pll library for enhanced functionalities
- Provide close coordination and facilitated Business Analysts to transform the business processes into technical specifications
- Development of Oracle Transactional Reporting using Oracle Reports 10g, XML Publisher and Business Intelligence Reporting using Oracle Discover and Daily Business Intelligence; that support senior Management and business analyst in decision making as well as efficiently support the daily business operations
- Developed User Training Manuals, Technical Design Documents, Data Conversion Documents and Testing Scripts Documentations

# Oracle E-Business Suite R12 Developer

03/2007 - 05/2010

Nishat Group of Cement Manufacturing

The largest cement manufacturing industry in Pakistan, the company is technological partner with Cisco for complete IP telephony and network infrastructure, Gold partner with Oracle Corp. and IBM licensed partner for IBM data servers and IT infrastructure hardware

- Development and integration of Gate Pass module within oracle e-business suite R12, the customized module greatly supported the tracking of goods and movement in and outside of manufacturing facilities
- Facilitated data extraction, data cleansing and data uploading from legacy system to target system by development of custom APIs, packages and custom tables to greatly improve the performance and accuracy
- Requirement gathering, format finalization and development of oracle reports using Reports 10g, Oracle discover administrator and discover viewer
- Extensively worked in Oracle SQL, PL/SQL, SQL\*Plus, SQL\*Loader, Query performance tuning, Created DDL scripts, created database objects like Tables, Indexes, Synonyms and Sequences

# Education

# BS (Hons) in Information Technology

2001-2005

University of Sindh

The University of Sindh is a public research university and one of the oldest universities in Pakistan and as of 2013 was ranked in eighth in terms of "general category" by the Higher Education Commission of Pakistan

# **Professional Development/Affiliations**

- Cloudera Data Scientist Python, Apache Spark, Machine Learning
- Oracle Fusion Order Management and Advance Pricing Support and Implementation
- Oracle Certified Professional 11g Advance PLSQL Developer (OCP 11g)
- Oracle Certified Professional 10g Forms Developer (OCP 10g)